# Mohammed Husamuddin

Github

#### **Profile**

I am an undergraduate computer science engineering student passionate about software and AI. I transform ideas into reality through elegant interfaces, prioritizing user experience and code quality.

Leadership: Google DSC Lead, Notion Campus Lead, IIT Bombay – E-Cell Ambassador, United Nations Academic Impact and MCN Fellowship 2024 (selected from 52,000+ applicants), StartUp advisor to the E-Cell BPDC

#### **Skills**

- Languages: Python, Java, C++, Matlab, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Assembly x86-64
- Frameworks & Libraries: Matplotlib, Pandas, Streamlit, TensorFlow, Numpy, Flask, BeautifulSoup, Scikit-Learn, OpenCv, Flower(Federated Learning), ShadCn, Taipy, ROSpy, Openai, Hugging Face, Google-Auth, Google Maps API, MkDocs
- Tools & Technologies: NextJs, React, Node.js, MySQL, Firebase, Vercel, Heroku, Git, Google Cloud Platform, Azure, AWS, Figma, REST, Docker, Linux, VS Code, Prisma, Notion, Power BI, Tableau, Linear
- Others: Product Management, Leadership, Standards and Procedures, Documentation, Cross Functional, Market Research, Competitive Analysis, Agile

# **Experience**

# **Google Developer Student Clubs**

#### Lead, BITS Pilani Dubai Chapter

Now Promoted to Google Developer Groups-Dubai

Confirmation Letter, Google

- Expanded chapter to largest campus community (350+ members), managing 26-person team across 5
- Developed and directed 4 internal and community applications/tools and 40+ long-term assets including automated scripts and internal web apps, increasing website traffic by 73% and documenting processes through SoP initiatives. SoP website

departments, implementing 3-tier structure, and overseeing 903+ student participation's and certifications.

#### Marketing Lead & Tech Exec, GDSC BITS Pilani Dubai Chapter

September 2022 - June 2023

June 2023 - September 2024

- Spearheaded marketing for 7 major events, attracting 432+ participants through strategic promotion and designing 53+ brand assets, resulting in a 100% increase in student engagement.
- Conducted UI/UX workshop focused on Google's Material UI framework, increasing technical skill adoption among attendees.

#### **Brio Tech**

# **Software Engineering Intern**

✓ View LoR ✓ View Certificate

July 2024 - August 2024

- Developed a Cloud Pricing Calculator that facilitated easy comparison of migration costs across cloud platforms, utilizing Azure API integration, Python web frameworks(Streamlit), and data analysis.
- Built a full-stack Sales Lead Email Generation Application that automated 80% of the lead generation process, increasing sales team productivity by 40%, utilizing LinkedIn's Rapid API, GPT-4 integration, and **Streamlit**(Now converting code base to React) for a responsive front-end
- Integrated Google Cloud Platform service accounts into the applications developed, enabling seamless and secure access to Google Cloud services without user intervention, learnt how to proficiently practise cloud security, IAM policies, and programmatic authentication in production environments.

### Styx, Pilani

#### **Founders Office and Software Developer**

☑ View Prototype ☑ View LoR

- Designed and developed a **security compliance dashboard MVP**, **increasing value by 27%** and gaining stakeholders approval
- Implemented software updates based on stakeholder requirements, meeting design specifications
- Pitched product to local and international investors & Engaged with customers and industry peers, developing strategies for 100% market reach. **Notable:** Contributed to securing 500,000 funding, backed by MapMyIndia **Business Development Intern & UI/UX Intern**January 2023 April 2023
- Led an in-depth analysis of business performance by conducting comprehensive assessments and presenting findings
- Created visual brand identity and assets using Figma for the MVP.

## PropReturns, Mumbai

#### Full Stack Developer & Data Science Intern

June 2023 - August 2023

March 2023 - January 2024

View Certificate

• Engineered data pipeline using Python and regex, cleaning web-scraped data and reducing manual entry by 73%, while developing a reusable UI component library that boosted developer productivity by 40% and improved system architecture, resulting in increase in UI consistency and flow efficiency.

# **BITS Motorsports, Dubai**

## **Head of Business & Marketing**

March 2022 - June 2023

BMS Dashboard View Certificate

- **Developed BMS Dashboard, boosting team efficiency by 30%** through integrated task and asset management, and sponsorship tracking for team members, using Next.is and React.
- Spearheaded comprehensive marketing initiatives, increasing project visibility by 45% through coordinated campaigns, creating sponsorship materials that led to a 37% boost in partner acquisition, and producing engaging video and brand assets that drove a 75% increase in social media engagement.

#### **Projects**

# Founded UniDash – One-stop platform for university resources unidash.com

Ongoing

• Developed student-focused tools using **React**, **Next.js**, **Shadcn UI**, **Redux**, **and Firebase**Deployed on Vercel and implemented as a **Progressive Web App (PWA)** for mobile installation

#### **University Geolocation Attendance System** (Academic Project)

Ongoing

• Developing a university-wide geolocation-based attendance system using **Google Maps**, **Geo Location**, **Elevation API**, **and React Native with Expo**, focused on accuracy, workload reduction, and a robust system.

# Federated Learning Model for IoT Attack Classification (Academic Project)

February 2024 - June 2024

• Designed a federated learning model using the **flower framework**, **pytorch** to classify 33 types of cyber attacks on edge devices with data privacy.

#### Website Development for Clients and University

Ongoing

☑ View Conference Site

#### Visual Hive and Value Vault- IG Page and Newsletter/Blog

Ongoing

☑ Visual Hive ☑ Value Vault Newsletter

• Grew a social media following of over **9,500+** through an Instagram page and **personal newsletter** by consistently sharing valuable insights and learnings, resulting in substantial audience engagement and growth.

# **Education**

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science, BITS Pilani Dubai Campus

September 2021 – Present

• Coursework: Computer Architecture, Artificial Intelligence, Computational Theory, Data Mining, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms,

High School Diploma, Delhi Private School, Sharjah

March 2007 - March 2021

• MUN Team, Played active cricket for the intra-school tournaments